ironplanet.com 2018-08-12

# IronPlanet - Terms and Conditions

******

Revised May 25, 2018

## Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement describes the privacy practices of the Ritchie Bros. multi-channel brand solutions identified in the chart below with respect to their collection, use, and disclosure of personal information, including information collected: 

  * at live auctions
  * through websites such as rbauction.com, ironplanet.com, govplanet.com, and truckplanet.com
  * through our mobile apps, and
  * when you contract with us to sell your equipment and other goods, or for value-added services such as financing, logistics or appraisals.

In this Privacy Statement, "personal information" means any information about an identified or identifiable individual, excluding any information that has been anonymized or that is excluded from the definition of "personal information" under applicable laws. 

Please read this Privacy Statement carefully as it affects your rights. 

References in this Privacy Statement to "Ritchie Bros.", a particular brand such as "Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers" or "IronPlanet", "we" or "us" refers to the Ritchie Bros. company that is the data controller and responsible for your information under this Privacy Statement as noted in the chart below. 

The information in this Privacy Statement may be supplemented or modified through other agreements with us or other notices we make available. We may update, replace or amend this Privacy Statement at any time. Any changes to this Privacy Statement will be posted on our websites and we will update the date of last revision. The revised Privacy Statement will be effective once posted unless we state otherwise. Please check back frequently. 

Where RBA has provided a translation of the English language version of this Privacy Statement, such translation is provided for your convenience only. To the extent there is any inconsistency between the English language version of this Privacy Statement and any such translation, the English language version takes precedence. 

This statement will notify you of: 

  1. Who the data controller of your personal information is
  2. What personal information we collect
  3. How the information is used
  4. With whom the information may be shared or disclosed
  5. What choices are available to you regarding the processing of your personal information
  6. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect your information from loss, misuse or alteration when under our control
  7. What rights you have with respect to your personal information and how you can exercise those rights

## Data Controllers

  1. When creating a user account on a website or otherwise using a website and mobile app of the brands listed below for non-transactional purposes, the data controller responsible for your personal information depends on your country of residence:  Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers   
---  
**Country of residence** |  **Ritchie Bros. controller** |  **Notice Address** |  **Lead Supervisory Authority (where applicable)**  
Anywhere our website or mobile app is accessible for use  |  Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers (Canada) Ltd.  |  9500 Glenlyon Parkway,   
Burnaby, BC V5J 0C6  |  _Anyone outside the EEA:_ Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada   
|  _Designated EEA Representative:_ Ritchie Bros. Shared Services B.V.  |  Concordiastraat 20  
4811 NB Breda, The Netherlands  |  Inside the EEA: Dutch Data Protection Authority   
_IronPlanet_ , _Marketplace-E_ , _GovPlanet_ , _TruckPlanet_ , _SalvageSale_ , _Kruse Energy_ , _Asset Appraisal Services_  
**Country of residence** |  **Ritchie Bros. controller** |  **Notice Address** |  **Lead Supervisory Authority (where applicable)**  
United States, and all other areas not mentioned in this section below where our website or mobile app is accessible for use  |  IronPlanet, Inc.  |  4000 Pine Lake Road,   
Lincoln, NE USA 68516  |     
Canada  |  IronPlanet Canada Ltd.  |  9500 Glenlyon Parkway,   
Burnaby, BC V5J 0C6  |  Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada   
United Kingdom  |  IronPlanet UK Limited  |  Concordiastraat 20  
4811 NB Breda, The Netherlands  |  Dutch Data Protection Authority   
European Economic Area (other than the UK), Middle-East and Africa  |  IronPlanet Limited  |  Concordiastraat 20  
4811 NB Breda, The Netherlands  |  Dutch Data Protection Authority   
Japan Super Auction   
**Country of residence** |  **Ritchie Bros. controller** |  **Notice Address** |  **Lead Supervisory Authority (where applicable)**  
Japan  |  Ritchie Bros.  
Auctioneers (Japan)  
KK  |  45-2771 Taragai  
Chiba Prefecture  
Narita  
287-0242  
Japan  |   
  2. When buying or selling equipment or other goods (in person, via the web or a mobile app) at the live events of the brands listed below, on their online marketplaces, or by private sale, when you purchase value-added services related to equipment, or when you otherwise engage with a brand below for transactional purposes in relation to equipment or other goods available for purchase and sale, the data controller responsible for your personal information depends on the location of the equipment or other goods:  _Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers_ , _Ritchie Bros. Private Treaty_  
---  
**Location of Equipment/Goods** |  **Ritchie Bros. controller** |  **Notice Address** |  **Lead Supervisory Authority (where applicable)**  
Canada or any other region not otherwise specified in this section  |  Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers (Canada) Ltd.  |  9500 Glenlyon Parkway,  
Burnaby, BC V5J 0C6  |  Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada   
United States  |  Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers (America) Inc.  |  4000 Pine Lake Road,  
Lincoln, NE USA 68516  |     
Mexico  |  Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers de Mexico S. de R.L. de C.V.  |  Carr. PolotitlÃ¡n, La EstaciÃ³n # 6 Col Centro. PolotitlÃ¡n, Estado de MÃ©xico, CP 54200  |  Instituto Nacional de Transparencia, Acceso a la InformaciÃ³n y ProtecciÃ³n de Datos Personales, INAI   
United Kingdom  |  Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers (UK) Limited  |  Concordiastraat 20  
4811 NB Breda, The Netherlands  |  Information Commissioner's Office   
The Netherlands  |  Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers B.V.  |  Concordiastraat 20  
4811 NB Breda, The Netherlands  |  Dutch Data Protection Authority   
Germany  |  Ritchie Bros. Deutschland GmbH  |  Concordiastraat 20  
4811 NB Breda, The Netherlands  |  Dutch Data Protection Authority   
France  |  Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers France SAS  |  Concordiastraat 20  
4811 NB Breda, The Netherlands  |  Dutch Data Protection Authority   
Italy  |  Ritchie Bros. Italia s.r.l.  |  Concordiastraat 20  
4811 NB Breda, The Netherlands  |  Dutch Data Protection Authority   
Spain  |  Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers (Spain) SLU.  |  Concordiastraat 20  
4811 NB Breda, The Netherlands  |  Dutch Data Protection Authority   
Australia  |  Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers Pty Ltd.  |  1-57 Burnside Road  
Yatala, QLD 4207  
Australia  |  Office of the Australian Information Commissioner   
New Zealand  |  Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers Pty Ltd.  |  1-57 Burnside Road  
Yatala, QLD 4207  
Australia  |  Office of the Privacy Commissioner New Zealand   
United Arab Emirates  |  Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers (ME) Limited  |  P.O. Box 16897, Jebel Ali Free Zone, Dubai, UAE  |     
_IronPlanet_ , _Marketplace-E_ , _GovPlanet_ , _TruckPlanet_ , _SalvageSale_ , _Kruse Energy_  
**Location of Equipment/Goods** |  **Ritchie Bros. controller** |  **Notice Address** |  **Lead Supervisory Authority (where applicable)**  
Canada  |  IronPlanet Canada Ltd.  |  9500 Glenlyon Parkway,  
Burnaby, BC V5J 0C6  |  Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada   
United States  |  IronPlanet, Inc.  |  4000 Pine Lake Road,  
Lincoln, NE USA 68516  |     
United Kingdom  |  IronPlanet UK Limited  |  Concordiastraat 20  
4811 NB Breda, The Netherlands  |  Information Commissioner's Office   
European Economic Area (other than UK), or any other region not otherwise specified in this section  |  IronPlanet Limited  |  Concordiastraat 20  
4811 NB Breda, The Netherlands  |  Dutch Data Protection Authority   
Australia  |  Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers Pty Ltd. dba IronPlanet Australia  |  1-57 Burnside Road  
Yatala, QLD 4207   
Australia  |  Office of the Australian Information Commissioner   
Japan Super Auction   
**Location of Equipment/Goods** |  **Ritchie Bros. controller** |  **Notice Address** |  **Lead Supervisory Authority (where applicable)**  
Japan  |  Ritchie Bros.  
Auctioneers (Japan)  
KK  |  45-2771 Taragai  
Chiba Prefecture  
Narita  
287-0242  
Japan  |  Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada   
  3. When inquiring about and applying for financing from Ritchie Bros. Financial Services, the data controller responsible for your personal information will depend on your location:  **Location** |  **Ritchie Bros. controller** |  **Notice Address** |  **Lead Supervisory Authority (where applicable)**  
---|---|---|---  
Canada and United States  |  Ritchie Bros. Financial Services Ltd.  |  9500 Glenlyon Parkway,   
Burnaby, BC V5J 0C6  |  Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada   
  4. When inquiring about and contracting for logistics services from Ritchie Bros. Logistics, the data controller responsible for your personal information will depend on your location:  **Location** |  **Ritchie Bros. controller** |  **Notice Address** |  **Lead Supervisory Authority (where applicable)**  
---|---|---|---  
European Economic Area  |  Ritchie Bros. B.V.  |  Concordiastraat 20  
4811 NB Breda, The Netherlands  |  Dutch Data Protection Authority   
  5. When inquiring about and contracting for paid appraisal services, the data controller responsible for your personal information will depend on your location:  Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers   
---  
**Location** |  **Ritchie Bros. controller** |  **Notice Address** |  **Lead Supervisory Authority (where applicable)**  
Canada, and all other areas not mentioned in this section below where our services are offered  |  Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers (Canada) Ltd.  |  9500 Glenlyon Parkway,   
Burnaby, BC V5J 0C6  |  _Anyone outside the EEA:_ Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada   
_Designated EEA Representative:_ Ritchie Bros. Shared Services B.V.  |  Concordiastraat 20  
4811 NB Breda, The Netherlands  |  _Inside the EEA:_ Dutch Data Protection Authority   
United States  |  Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers (America) Inc.  |  4000 Pine Lake Road,  
Lincoln, NE USA 68516  |     
Asset Appraisal Services   
**Location** |  **Ritchie Bros. controller** |  **Notice Address** |  **Lead Supervisory Authority (where applicable)**  
United States  |  IronPlanet, Inc.  |  4000 Pine Lake Road,  
Lincoln, NE USA 68516  |     

## Information Collection

We collect personal information from individuals when they voluntarily take certain actions with us such as: 

  * registering and activating an online account
  * updating your industry or geographic preferences
  * entering into an agreement to sell their assets
  * registering to bid at a sales event
  * completing the purchase of assets at a sales event
  * applying for financing, logistics services, appraisal services or other value-added services
  * requesting information about our services and products or marketing communications
  * filling out surveys, feedback forms or participating in contents or customer focus groups
  * interacting with our public forums or communities (if you join our online community platform, any content you post in the discussion forums will be accessible to all other community participants. If you do not want personal information to be appear, please do not submit or post this information in any public area)

We also collect your information automatically when you use our online sites, apps and services or attend our live events by way of: 

  * audio/video or other surveillance means to monitor our physical premises
  * cookies, web beacons, unique identifiers and similar technologies to collect information about the pages you view, links you click, and other actions you take when using our services or within our advertising or email content 
  * web server logs and other means to record connection information (such as statistics on your page views, traffic to and from sites, referral URLs, IP addresses, web log information, device information and where your setting permit, location information)

Registered users with an account may add additional accounts to their primary account created when first registering. If you choose to create multiple accounts under you profile, you acknowledge that all the information associated with those accounts will be governed by this Privacy Statement. 

## Information Use

We use information collected from individuals to provide products or services, to respond to requests for information regarding our products and services, to protect our rights and the rights of others, to provide you with digital advertising and marketing, provide customer service, to detect, prevent, mitigate and investigate fraudulent or illegal activities, and to communicate with you about important site and service announcements or updates. Depending on the preferences you've communicated to us, we may communicate with you by email, phone or regular mail. 

We use your personal information for a range of different business purposes and according to different legal bases of processing. 

**Necessary to fulfil a contract with you and provide you services and products, take steps at your request, to comply with our legal obligations, to protect vital interests, or as may be required in the public interest.** This includes to:

  * collect and pay fees or money owed, or otherwise process payments
  * contact you to troubleshoot account issues, resolve a dispute (including using surveillance footage) or otherwise provide customer service
  * provide the services requested or contracted for by you
  * process applications for services
  * prepare paid appraisals and valuations
  * approve and monitor bidding limits, detect, suppress or take other actions regarding suspected illegal activities, identity verification, suspected fraud, or a violation of our account terms and conditions, our policies or agreements
  * provide you log-in access to our websites and mobile apps
  * ensure your physical safety at our facilities
  * work with third party partners to provide you with value-added services requested

**To pursue our legitimate interest (or our common legitimate interests with a third party) where your rights and freedoms do not outweigh these interests.** This includes to:

  * deliver relevant content and advertising by: 
    * generating and analyzing reports and data about your transactions history, patterns of usage of our websites or after combining your information with information relating to your use of services provided by us;
    * personalizing our online services based on your customized preferences and usage, and
    * working with unaffiliated third-party service providers who help deliver ads relating to products and services you've purchased or products and services offered by us which we believe are consistent with your interests when browsing the web
  * contact you via email or regular mail to keep you informed about sales events, equipment, events and other offers about Ritchie Bros. multiple brand solutions, as permitted by applicable law
  * contact you by phone where permitted b applicable law to offer products and services that may be of interest to you such as equipment financing opportunities
  * improve our services, products, websites, mobile apps, and auction facilities
  * understand the secondary equipment market and develop new products, services or features
  * contact you for feedback or to fill out occasional surveys to help us monitor our performance and improve our service offering (if you provide us with the feedback, we can use your remarks, suggestions, writings or comments from surveys or other feedback mechanisms as we so determine without your further consent and without compensation or any other interests or rights - don't worry, we won't identify you in association with feedback without your prior permission)
  * monitor and improve the security of our sites and apps

**With your consent.** This includes to: 

  * keep you informed about sales events, equipment, events and other offers by email or regular mail
  * provide you with marketing about the Ritchie Bros. brand solutions
  * use your precise geo-location in our apps to provide location based services
  * share certain limited information with unaffiliated third-parties to provide you with value-added services or information about products and services you request

You can withdraw your consent at any time. Contact us as indicated at the end of this Privacy Statement for further instructions or details. 

## International Transfer and Storage

Data we collect is transferred to central databases located in various countries, including Canada, Europe and the United States. In addition, our personnel and our third-party service providers whom we transfer your information to may also store and access (and in the case of service providers, onward transfer) your personal information in other countries. These countries may offer a different level of data protection and may have different data protection rules than your country of residence. In certain circumstances courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies or security authorities in those other foreign jurisdictions may be entitled to access your information. When we transfer your personal information, we ensure that there are in place contractual and technological means designed to mitigate the threat of unauthorized access, use or disclosure of your information, and where appropriate, to ensure there is a lawful basis for the initial transfer or onward transfer of the information. Please contact us as noted below at the end of this Privacy Statement if you have any questions about our policies regarding service providers outside of Canada. 

## Information Sharing and Disclosure

**Original Equipment Manufacturers.** If you make a bid during a Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers or an IronPlanet sales event, we may share your personal information with the original equipment manufacturer (OEM) of the offered lot you bid on and any of the OEM's dealers or representatives in your geographic area and their respective service providers. OEMs and their dealers or representatives use this information to pursue their legitimate interest of understanding the lifecycle of their equipment and the secondary market for their equipment, to communicate with you about their products and services, and for other purposes disclosed in their privacy policies. Once disclosed, this information will be governed by the OEM's or the OEM dealer's privacy policy and will be subject to the laws of the jurisdiction in which the OEM or OEM dealer processes the information. See "Choice / Opt-Out" below for information on how to opt-out of this sharing. We have no liability for information used by the OEM, its dealers, representatives and service providers. You may request information on which OEM your personal information was disclosed to by contacting us at [dataprotection@ritchiebros.com](mailto:dataprotection@ritchiebros.com), attention: Data Protection Officer or by mail at Ritchie Bros., 9500 Glenlyon Parkway, Burnaby, BC, Canada, V5J 0C6. 

**Affiliated Entities.** In pursuit of our common interests we share personal information among members of the Ritchie Bros. corporate family for purposes consistent with this Privacy Statement. Where permitted by law, you may receive promotional and other communications from these related family members. See here for more information: www.rbauction.com/data-sharing-faq 

**Unaffiliated Third Parties.** We in our legitimate interest, and in certain cases, where necessary to ensure we perform our contractual obligations with you, may use third parties to perform functions in connection with our services (for example, email marketing automation, market research, data analytics and data enhancement, fraud detection, OFAC compliance verification, customer service, site operations and hosting, systems management, accounting, auditing, billing, reconciliation, and collection activities). We may transfer limited information about you into their platforms so that we can utilize their services. If we partner with another party to provide specific services (for example, extended service plans, transportation services or equipment refurbishment services), and you request or contract for these services, we will share the contact information or other information necessary for the third party to provide the requested services. We may also disclose personal information to legal, financial, and other professional advisors and to our lenders or insurers in connection with the operation of our business where such parties have agreed to confidentiality restrictions. 

**Financing Partners.** We may, in our legitimate interests, share your information with our trusted broker partners who provide you with access to unique, customized lending or financing products that we believe may be of value to you. We also share your personal information with our lending partners that you provide us when you apply to be approved for financing through Ritchie Bros. Financial Services. 

**Customer Payment Solutions.** If you have elected to complete a purchase of an asset in a currency other than the currency noted, in order to complete your transaction, the payment and currency exchange will be provided through a third-party financial institution. In order to complete the transaction, we may need to collect personal information and share this personal information with the third-party financial institution providing payment solutions. During this process, we will seek your further approval and notify you of the personal information being collected by us and provided to the third-party financial institution. Once disclosed, this information will be governed by the third-party financial institution's privacy policy and will be subject to the laws of the jurisdiction in which the third-party financial institution processes the information. 

**Anonymous Information.** We may share aggregated demographic information or other de-identified information with our trusted third-party partners. 

**Business Changes.** If we become involved in a merger, acquisition, sale of assets, joint venture, securities offering, bankruptcy, reorganization, liquidation, dissolution, or other transaction or if the ownership of all or substantially all of our business otherwise changes, we may share or transfer your information in our legitimate interest and in certain cases, where necessary to ensure we perform our contractual obligations with you, to a third party or parties in connection with such business change. 

**Investigations and Law.** To the extent required or permitted by applicable law, we disclose information about you to third parties to: 

  * Comply with law, in response to subpoenas, warrants, or court orders, or in connection with any legal process or cooperate with government or law enforcement officials or private parties, including laws outside of your country of residence;
  * Protect our rights, reputation, safety and property, or that of our customers or others;
  * Protect against legal liability;
  * Establish or exercise our rights to defend against legal claims; or
  * To investigate, prevent or take action regarding suspected illegal activities, suspected fraud, the rights, reputation, safety or property of us, customers or others, violation of our account terms and conditions, our policies or agreements or as otherwise required or permitted by applicable law.

## Cookies and Other Technologies

When you interact with our websites or mobile apps, we or our authorized third-party service providers may place cookies, web beacons (also known as action tags or single-pixel gifs), and other non-cookie based technologies on your device to collect and store information that helps us track and analyze usage, provide a more efficient and personalized experience to our users, and to personalize online display advertising tailored to users' interests. This information collected by us may be associated with personal information we already have or collect from other sources for the purposes noted above under "Information Use". 

Some of these technologies may be permanently placed on your device until you choose to remove them (i.e. persistent cookies); while others are temporary and are removed after you close your browser (i.e. session cookies). You are always free to block our cookies if your browser or device permits, although doing so may interfere with your use of some of our services' and websites' features or content. For more information on how you can block, delete, or disable cookies, please review your specific browser or device settings. Please review your browser settings for further details. Please also note that you may choose to opt-out of some of these technologies as explained in "Choice/Opt Out" below. 

Our use of these technologies falls into four categories: 

  1. Operationally necessary - These technologies are used to permit access to our websites or services and use certain features such as maintaining logged-in status for your account while using a website, as well as enabling you to move around it and use its features.
  2. Functionality related - We use these technologies so we can remember your preferences while browsing websites and to provide enhanced and more personalized content and features, such as saved equipment searches. In order to permit your connection and use of our websites and services, we receive and record usage data about your device and browser (see above). If you access the website from a mobile or other device, we may collect a unique device identifier assigned to that device, geolocation data (where permitted in your device settings), or other transactional information for that device.
  3. Performance related - We and/or our service providers may use analytics and testing technologies to collect information about your usage and interaction with our services and websites, for instance web page views or interaction with a link or other content. We use this information to understand overall usage patterns of our visitors and determine whether certain content is effective or not. We do not permit any of these service providers to use any of your personal information collected on our websites for their own purposes.
  4. Advertising related - These technologies are used by us and our service providers to deliver advertising or personalized emails we believe are relevant to you and your interests. For example, we may use first-party cookies and web beacons to deliver content, including personalized ads, we believe are relevant to your interests, on our websites or on third party sites. This means that when you are on websites other than our websites, you may be shown advertising based on your activity on our websites. These technologies may also be used to help measure the effectiveness of our ad campaigns. These technologies remember what you've looked at on our websites as well as, among other things, IP address, browser type, webpage visited prior to our websites, and the subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over. 

Third-party advertisers and other organizations also use their own third-party cookies or plug-ins to collect information about your activities on our websites and/or the advertisements you have clicked on. This information, which may be combined with other information acquired from third parties, may be used by them to serve advertisements on third party sites that they believe are most likely to be of interest to you based on content you have viewed. Third-party advertisers may also use this information to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to track aggregate usage statistics. We do not control these third-parties' processing of your information which is governed by the privacy policies of the third parties employing these cookies. To learn about these cookies and to disable or reject third-party cookies, please refer to the relevant third party's website or "Choice/Opt Out" below.

## Security

While we take reasonable administrative, technical and physical measures to protect the information you submit or that we collect online and offline against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure, or modification, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. No Internet, email or mobile application transmission is ever fully secure or error free. If you believe your Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers account has been abused, please contact us at [csg@rbauction.com](mailto:csg@rbauction.com). If you believe your IronPlanet account has been abused, please contact us at [customercare@ironplanet.com](mailto:customercare@ironplanet.com). To the extent permitted by applicable law, you also agree that we will not be liable for access to or the use or acquisition of your information by any third party without our knowledge or consent in contravention of our safeguards. 

## Children

We do not attempt to collect personal information from individuals under the age of 18. Note that we cannot always determine if a user of our websites or apps is a child under the age of 18. 

## Links

Our websites contain links to other sites, including sites maintained by our third party partners for the provision of online payment services and online shipping quotes. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to read the privacy statements of all websites that collect personal information. 

## Choice / Opt-Out

You have a choice about how we use your personal information to communicate with you and how we provide relevant advertising.

**1\. Email Communications**

We use your email address to communicate with you in order to fulfill any contractual obligations with you, including those associated with your online account. In addition, where permitted by applicable law, we may send you relevant marketing communication if you have registered and created a profile through one of our websites (including rbauction.com, ironplanet.com, truckplanet.com, or govplanet.com) and agreed to our terms of use for your account. We may also send you marketing communications if you have registered to sell or bid in person at any of our live sales events and agreed to our terms at the time of registration. In certain jurisdictions, by doing so, you infer or imply your consent. If you reside in a country that requires that we obtain your express consent separately, we will ask for you to expressly opt-into communications. Marketing communications may come from the Ritchie Bros. entity that you contracted with when registering an account or registering to sell or bid, or from an affiliated Ritchie Bros. entity that provides goods or services that we think may be of interest to you. If you are receiving marketing emails, you can unsubscribe from these marketing emails by clicking the unsubscribe link in any marketing email you receive. 

**2\. Original Equipment Manufacturers**

If you are a bidder and do not want your personal information shared with the original equipment manufacturer ("OEM") of any offered lot and any of the OEM's dealers, representatives and service providers, please contact [OEMoptout@rbauction.com](mailto:OEMoptout@rbauction.com). We will communicate your preference to the OEMs on a go-forward basis; however, we have no liability for information previously obtained and used by the OEM, its dealers, representatives and service providers. 

**3\. Advertising, Personalization & Analytics **

As of the date of this Privacy Statement, we use the following service providers to assist us with serving interest based ads and to analyze your interactions with our services, websites and apps using the technologies described above under "Cookies and Other Technologies". Please note that this list is subject to change. You may contact us as noted at the end of this Privacy Statement for up-to-date information on the service providers we are using. 

_Google Analytics and Google Optimize_ \- These cookies allow us to understand how you use and interact with our services. If you don't want data to be collected and reported by Google Analytics or Google Optimize, you can opt-out by installing a browser add-on. Visit the [Google Analytics opt-out page](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en) for more information. 

_Google DoubleClick and AdSense_ \- We use these services to serve advertisements we think may be of interest to you based on your previous interactions with our websites and your activity across multiple other websites. You may opt-out of the DoubleClick cookie for interest based advertising by updating your Google [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/). There you will also find instructions to permanently opt-out through the use of an installed browser plug-in. 

_Lotame and TradeDesk_ \- These service providers assist us in our digital advertising campaigns based on your interaction with our websites and to better understand the effectiveness of our digital ads. You can find more information about their privacy practices by reviewing their respective privacy policies - [Lotame](https://www.lotame.com/legal/) and [TradeDesk](https://www.thetradedesk.com/general/privacy-policy). You can opt-out of the collection of information by these service providers by visiting their respective opt-out webpages and following the relevant instructions - [Lotame](https://www.lotame.com/opt-out-preference-manager/) and [TradeDesk](http://www.adsrvr.org/). 

_HubSpot, Marketo_ \- If you receive marketing communications from us, we use HubSpot and Marketo to collect and use information about your visits and interactions with our websites or email communications to send you personalized email alerts for goods and services. You may unsubscribe from these marketing emails by clicking the unsubscribe link in any email received. To opt-out of further collection of your information for these personalized emails, you can change your browser settings as described in "Cookies and Other Technologies" above. 

_Monetate_ \- We work with Monetate to test and adapt our websites to offer an improved customer experience. We also use Monetate to provide personalized content on our websites based on your interactions with our websites, our advertisements or our email communications. More information on how Monetate processes information is found [here](http://www.monetate.com/platform-privacy-policy). To opt-out of further collection of your information for this personalized experience, you can change your browser settings as described in "Cookies and Other Technologies" above. 

_Hotjar and Optimizely_ \- We use these services to help us analyze and test your interactions with our websites. The information collected is then used to optimize your experience while using our websites. You can find more information about their privacy practices by reviewing their respective privacy policies - click [here](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy) for Hotjar and click [here](https://www.optimizely.com/privacy/) for Optimizely. You can opt-out of further data collection by these service providers by visiting their respective opt-out webpages and following the relevant instructions - click [here](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out) for Hotjar and click [here](https://www.optimizely.com/opt_out/) for Optimizely. 

_Criteo_ \- We use the services of Criteo to collect and use anonymous information about your visits to and interactions with our websites and others across the internet to personalize online ads for goods and services. We take appropriate steps to ensure that the recipient safeguards this personal information and uses the information only for authorized purposes. For more information about Criteo's privacy practices generally or to opt-out of further anonymous data collection by Criteo, please [click here](http://www.criteo.com/privacy/). To opt-out of our sharing of your limited, non-sensitive personal information, please contact us at [csg@rbauction.com](mailto:csg@rbauction.com). 

_Social Media Plugins_ \- We invite you to socialize and share certain content on our websites with others using your social media tools such as Facebook, Twitter, Google+ and LinkedIn. If you choose to use these tools, you may be sharing certain profile elements, including your comments. This sharing is subject to each social media program's privacy policies. 

_Facebook Custom Audiences_ \- We use this service to ask Facebook to show you ads that are customized based on your interactions with our websites or our Facebook applications and to measure how you interact with those ads. We may do this using web tracking tools or by converting the email address, phone number or other contact information you have provided to us into a unique value that Facebook may compare to a unique value created from information you provided to Facebook. [Facebook's Data Use Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) describes how Facebook protects information collected through Facebook Custom Audiences. You may opt-out of Facebook Custom Audiences by visiting [Facebook's ad preferences page, logging-in](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/) and adjusting your settings. 

Note that opt-out choices selected above may be browser and device specific. As well, deleting cookies can remove your opt-out preferences, so you may need to periodically refresh your opt-out preferences. 

Please also note that opting-out of our interest based advertising is not the same thing as opting out of ads. You will still see ads, possibly the same ads, and you may even see our ads, however, they will be random. 

For more information about targeting and advertising cookies and how you can opt-out from certain third parties generally, visit: 

  * Network Advertising Initiative: http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/
  * U.S. Digital Advertising Alliance: http://www.aboutads.info/choices/
  * Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada: http://youradchoices.ca/
  * European Digital Advertising Alliance: http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/

To set "Limit Ad Tracking" on various iOS devices, please [click here](http://support.apple.com/kb/ht4228). 

To opt-out of Google interest-based ads on Android, open your Google Settings app > Ads > Enable "Opt out of interest-based advertising" 

**_Do Not Track_.** At this time, we do not respond to "Do Not Track" signals sent from web browsers. 

## Your Rights

You may request to exercise any of the rights described in this part by contacting our Data Protection Officer as noted below under "Contacting Us". Note, we may ask you to verify your identity before taking further action on your request. 

**Access to Information.** In some jurisdictions, applicable law may entitle you to information about who, where, why, how and for long we will hold and process information about you. Access to this information may be subject to payment to cover our costs in providing you with the information requested. Should you wish to receive details about personal information that we hold about you please contact us using the contact details below. 

**California Privacy Rights.** California law entitles residents to ask us once per calendar year for a notice describing what categories of personal information we share with third parties or with our corporate affiliates for those entities direct marketing purposes. If you want to request a notice or have any questions about our privacy practices, please contact as noted below. 

**Rectification of Inaccurate or Incomplete Data.** You have the right to ask us to correct inaccurate or incomplete personal data concerning you. Please contact us using the details below. You may also use your online account profile page to review and edit some of your personal information. 

**Data Portability.** In some jurisdictions, applicable law may entitle you to request copies of personal information you provided to us in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format and/or request us to transmit this information to another service provider (where technically feasible). 

**Data Retention and Erasure.** We generally retain your personal information for as long as is necessary for the performance of the contract between you and us and to comply with our legal obligations. If you no longer want us to use your personal information to provide our services to you, you can request that we erase your personal information and close your 

  * We may retain some of the data as necessary for our legitimate business interests, such as fraud detection and prevention, for example to prevent a user from re-opening an account after being suspended.
  * We may retain and use the data to the extent necessary to comply with our tax, legal reporting and auditing obligations.
  * Some residual copies of the data will remain in our backup systems for a limited period of time.

**Withdrawing Consent and Restricting Processing.** Where you have provided your consent to our processing of your personal information you may withdraw your consent at any time by sending a communication to us at the location below specifying which consent you want to withdraw. Please note that the withdrawal of your consent does not affect the lawfulness of any processing activities based on such consent before its withdrawal. Additionally, in some jurisdictions, applicable law may give you the right to restrict the ways in which we use your personal information, in particular where: 

  * you contest the accuracy of your personal information; 
  * the processing is unlawful and you oppose the erasure of your personal information;
  * we no longer need your personal information for the purposes of the processing, but you require the information for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or 
  * you have objected to the processing based on the grounds described in the next paragraph below and pending the verification whether we have legitimate grounds which override your own.

**Objecting to Processing.** In some jurisdictions, applicable law may entitle you to require us not to process your personal data for certain specific purposes (including profiling) where such processing is based on our legitimate interest. If you object to such processing we will no longer process your personal information for these purposes unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for such processing or such processing is required for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. 

Where your personal information is processed for direct marketing purposes, you may, at any time ask us to cease processing your data for these direct marketing purposes by sending an e-mail to opt-out at the email address below. 

**Lodging Complaints.** You have the right to lodge complaints about the data processing activities we carry out before competent data protection authorities. We hope though that if you reach out to us first, we can resolve your complaint amicably. If not, then refer to the chart above to see which supervisory authority to contact. 

## Contact Us

Feel free to reach out to us by emailing us at [dataprotection@ritchiebros.com](mailto:dataprotection@ritchiebros.com) or by regular mail using the addresses noted in the table above under "Data Controllers". 

******
